Hello English learners, welcome back to another lesson with us at EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的又一课。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we don't feel very good.
今天我们感觉不太好。
That's right.
没错。
Actually, in this lesson we're talking about a hangover.
实际上，这节课我们要聊的是宿醉。
Hangover, wow, that's an interesting word.
宿醉，哇，这个词挺有意思的。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Well, when you drink beer or wine or vodka, and you drink too much of it, the next morning
嗯，当你喝啤酒、葡萄酒或伏特加，而且喝得太多时，第二天早上
you have a hangover.
你就会宿醉。
Aha, okay, so a lot of our listeners have probably experienced a hangover before.
啊哈，好的，所以很多听众可能以前都经历过宿醉。
It's very likely.
很有可能。
But the problem is when you have to go to work the next day.
但问题是你第二天还得去上班。
Yes, and you might need to actually miss work, but you need some good words and phrases to
是的，你可能需要请假，但你需要一些好的词汇和短语来
describe how bad you feel.
描述你有多难受。
Okay, so let's listen to this dialogue for the first time.
好的，那我们第一次来听这段对话。
We have a guy describing his hangover and why he missed work that day.
有个家伙在描述他的宿醉，以及他那天为什么没去上班。
Are you okay, man?
你还好吗，哥们？
You don't look very well.
你看起来不太舒服。
I feel terrible.
我感觉糟透了。
I went out last night with Trevor and things got a little out of hand.
昨晚我和Trevor出去了，事情有点失控了。
Nice, so where did you guys go?
不错，那你们去了哪儿？
We hit up a couple of local bars and met up with some friends.
我们去了几家当地的酒吧，和一些朋友碰了面。
Everything was cool until Mike came along and it turned out that it was his birthday
本来一切都挺好的，直到Mike来了，结果发现昨天是他的生日。
yesterday.
昨天。
Oh no, Mike's birthday is a drink fest for sure.
哦不，Mike的生日肯定是一场喝酒狂欢。
Tell me about it.
可不是嘛。
We drank everything in the bar.
我们把酒吧里的酒都喝光了。
Is that why you missed work today?
这就是你今天没上班的原因吗？
Yeah, I woke up this morning feeling really nauseous.
是啊，我今天早上醒来觉得特别恶心。
I threw up like five times.
我吐了大概五次。
I was so dehydrated that I drank a gallon of water and my head has been pounding all
我严重脱水，喝了一加仑的水，而且我的头整天都在
day.
砰砰地疼。
I swear, I am never going to drink again.
我发誓，我再也不喝酒了。
Too bad, man.
真可惜，哥们。
Tonight is Tracy's going away party and she asked if you were going to go.
今晚是Tracy的告别派对，她问你会不会去。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
I'm there.
我去。
All right, so he's never drinking again, but then at the next chance for a party, he's
好吧，所以他再也不喝酒了，但一有派对的机会，他就
already ready to go.
已经准备好要去了。
I think that's the typical lie of every person that drinks.
我觉得这是每个喝酒的人典型的谎言。
They say, I'll never drink again, but a week later or a month later, there they are again.
他们说，我再也不喝了，但一周后或一个月后，他们又出现了。
Or a day later.
或者一天后。
All right, so we saw some great vocab here, so let's look at it now in Language Takeaway.
好的，我们在这里看到了一些很棒的词汇，现在在“语言要点”部分来看看它们。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
I'm going to look at five words here.
我要看五个词。
Now, the first one, they talked about how Mike's birthday is a drink fest.
第一个，他们谈到Mike的生日是一场喝酒狂欢。
A drink fest.
喝酒狂欢。
It's a drink fest.
这是一场喝酒狂欢。
All right, so we have this word, drink fest.
好的，我们有这个词，喝酒狂欢。
Now, what is this fest part?
那这个“狂欢”部分是什么意思？
Well, maybe you recognize the word, Oktoberfest.
嗯，你可能认识这个词，啤酒节。
Okay, or festival.
好的，或者节日。
So fest is like a party.
所以“狂欢”就像是一个派对。
There's lots of food.
有很多食物。
There's lots of drink.
有很多饮料。
A drink fest is an event where there's a lot of drinks.
喝酒狂欢就是一个有很多饮料的活动。
Okay, so can I have different types of fests?
好的，那我可以有不同类型的“狂欢”吗？
Yeah, this is a really informal sort of slang way of saying there's lots of something.
是的，这是一种非常非正式的俚语说法，表示有很多某样东西。
So I could say, oh my God, it's a puppy fest.
所以我可以这么说，哦天哪，这是一场小狗狂欢。
So there are a lot of puppies.
意思是那里有很多小狗。
Or I can say like a fast food fest.
或者我可以说像快餐狂欢。
Okay, so you're eating a lot of fast food.
好的，所以你吃了很多快餐。
There's a lot of fast food.
有很多快餐。
All right, so fest, interesting.
好的，所以“狂欢”这个词很有意思。
Now, when he was describing his hangover, he said that he felt really nauseous.
现在，当他描述宿醉时，他说他感觉非常恶心。
Nauseous.
恶心。
Now, I always have a hard time spelling this word.
我拼这个词总是很费劲。
So N-A-U-S-E-O-U-S, nauseous.
所以是N-A-U-S-E-O-U-S，恶心。
Nauseous.
恶心。
It kind of seems like you should say nauseous.
听起来好像应该读成“nauseous”。
Right, but-
对，但是——
But you say nauseous.
但你读成“nauseous”。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, so when you're feeling nauseous, what do you feel like?
好的，当你感到恶心时，你是什么感觉？
So you feel dizzy.
你会觉得头晕。
You don't feel very well.
你感觉不太舒服。
Like your stomach hurts.
比如胃疼。
Yeah, and your head is kind of spinning.
是的，而且头有点晕。
Okay, and you feel like you might throw up.
好的，而且你觉得可能会吐。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
Now this word that you just mentioned, throw up, is actually our next word and well, we're
你刚才提到的这个词，“吐”，实际上是我们的下一个词，嗯，我们
not going to describe it.
就不描述了。
Why don't we just listen to a person throwing up?
不如我们直接听一个人吐的声音？
Oh, Marco, that was horrible.
哦，Marco，那太恶心了。
Well, that's the only way we could actually explain throw up.
嗯，这是唯一能解释“吐”的方式。
It's kind of a hard word to explain, but I'm sure everyone understands now what it means,
这个词有点难解释，但我相信现在大家都明白它的意思了，
right?
对吧？
Okay, the word is to throw up.
好的，这个词是“吐”。
To throw up.
吐。
Our next word.
我们的下一个词。
Now, our guy who's hungover, he said, I was so dehydrated.
现在，我们宿醉的家伙说，我严重脱水。
Dehydrated.
脱水。
To be dehydrated.
So this is an adjective and it means that I have no water in my body.
所以这是一个形容词，意思是我体内没有水分了。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so I am dehydrated.
好的，所以我脱水了。
I need water.
我需要水。
That common feeling after drinking too much beer, huh?
喝太多啤酒后常见的感觉，是吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Now our final word.
现在我们的最后一个词。
He said he had a headache and he said, my head's been pounding all day.
他说他头疼，而且他说，我的头整天都在砰砰地疼。
Okay, so his head has been pounding all day.
好的，所以他的头整天都在砰砰地疼。
Now this verb, pounding, it sounds like this.
现在这个动词，“砰砰地疼”，听起来像这样。
Alright, so a clear example of what your head feels like when you have this very bad headache.
好的，所以这是一个很清楚的例子，说明你头疼得厉害时头的感觉。
You can also say, I have a pounding headache.
你也可以说，我头疼得砰砰响。
I have a pounding headache.
我头疼得砰砰响。
Exactly.
没错。
Or my head is pounding.
或者我的头在砰砰地疼。
Alright so five great words that we just looked at right now.
好的，我们刚刚看了五个很棒的词。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue a second time.
那我们再听一遍对话吧。
Let's slow it down just a little bit and then we'll come back and take a look at some phrases.
我们放慢一点速度，然后回来看看一些短语。
Are you okay, man?
你还好吗，哥们？
You don't look very well.
你看起来不太舒服。
I feel terrible.
我感觉糟透了。
I went out last night with Trevor and things got a little out of hand.
昨晚我和Trevor出去了，事情有点失控了。
Nice.
不错。
So where did you guys go?
那你们去了哪儿？
We hit up a couple of local bars and met up with some friends.
我们去了几家当地的酒吧，和一些朋友碰了面。
Everything was cool until Mike came along and it turned out that it was his birthday
本来一切都挺好的，直到Mike来了，结果发现昨天是他的生日。
yesterday.
昨天。
Oh no.
哦不。
Mike's birthday is a drink fest for sure.
Mike的生日肯定是一场喝酒狂欢。
Tell me about it.
可不是嘛。
We drank everything in the bar.
我们把酒吧里的酒都喝光了。
Is that why you missed work today?
这就是你今天没上班的原因吗？
Yeah, I woke up this morning feeling really nauseous.
是啊，我今天早上醒来觉得特别恶心。
I threw up like five times.
我吐了大概五次。
Ew.
呃。
I was so dehydrated that I drank a gallon of water and my head has been pounding all
我严重脱水，喝了一加仑的水，而且我的头整天都在
day.
砰砰地疼。
I swear I am never going to drink again.
我发誓我再也不喝酒了。
Too bad, man.
真可惜，哥们。
Tonight is Tracy's going away party and she asked if you were going to go.
今晚是Tracy的告别派对，她问你会不会去。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
I'm there.
我去。
Alright, well that was a little easier to understand this time.
好的，这次听起来容易理解一些了。
Now you mentioned that we've got some great phrases so let's go to them now in Fluency
你提到我们有一些很棒的短语，那我们现在就去“流利度构建”部分看看它们。
Builder.
流利度构建。
Fluency Builder.
Alright, so as we heard in the dialogue, the party was, I think it was a great party, right?
好的，就像我们在对话中听到的，那个派对，我觉得是个很棒的派对，对吧？
Well, it sounds like it was fantastic.
嗯，听起来很棒。
Well, apparently it was a great party and he said that he went out with Trevor and things
嗯，显然那是个很棒的派对，他说他和Trevor出去了，事情
got a little out of hand.
有点失控了。
Things got a little out of hand.
事情有点失控了。
Right, so things got a little out of hand.
对，所以事情有点失控了。
Now to get out of hand, what's that mean?
那“失控”是什么意思？
Well, we have some examples so let's listen to a couple of them before we explain it.
嗯，我们有一些例子，在解释之前先听几个。
Example 1.
例子1。
Honey, the kids are getting a little out of hand.
亲爱的，孩子们有点失控了。
Can you do something?
你能管管吗？
Example 2.
例子2。
Guys, this argument is getting out of hand.
伙计们，这场争论有点失控了。
Let's all calm down.
我们都冷静一下。
Example 3.
例子3。
The party last night got out of hand.
昨晚的派对失控了。
The neighbors called the police.
邻居报了警。
Okay, so when things get out of hand, you lose control.
好的，所以当事情失控时，你就失去了控制。
Exactly, they get out of control just a little bit maybe.
没错，可能有点失控了。
Yeah, go a little crazy.
是的，有点疯狂。
Alright so things got a little out of hand.
好的，所以事情有点失控了。
Now the opposite of this was everything was cool.
现在相反的情况是“一切都挺好的”。
Everything was cool.
一切都挺好的。
So everything was cool.
所以一切都挺好的。
So basically everything was okay, everything was relaxed, everything was going fine.
所以基本上一切都很好，一切都很放松，一切都很顺利。
Exactly, and then Mike came along and then things got a little out of hand.
没错，然后Mike来了，事情就有点失控了。
Oh, that Mike.
哦，那个Mike。
And now for our last phrase.
现在来看我们最后一个短语。
He was describing that Mike's birthday party was a drink fest, right?
他描述Mike的生日派对是一场喝酒狂欢，对吧？
And then his friend agreed.
然后他的朋友表示同意。
He said, tell me about it.
他说，可不是嘛。
Tell me about it.
可不是嘛。
Now what does this mean exactly when he says tell me about it?
那他说“可不是嘛”到底是什么意思？
Basically it means I completely understand.
基本上意思是“我完全理解”。
I completely agree with you.
我完全同意你的看法。
So I could say, oh my god Marco, it's so hot outside today.
所以我可以这么说，哦天哪Marco，今天外面好热。
And I would say, I know, tell me about it.
然后我会说，我知道，可不是嘛。
So I'm saying, yeah, I agree with you, you are right.
所以我在说，是的，我同意你，你说得对。
Very good.
非常好。
So these phrases, okay, so three great phrases that we just looked at.
所以这些短语，好的，我们刚刚看了三个很棒的短语。
Let's listen to our dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and talk a little
我们最后再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一会儿。
bit more.
再聊一会儿。
Are you okay, man?
你还好吗，哥们？
You don't look very well.
你看起来不太舒服。
I feel terrible.
我感觉糟透了。
I went out last night with Trevor and things got a little out of hand.
昨晚我和Trevor出去了，事情有点失控了。
Nice.
不错。
So where did you guys go?
那你们去了哪儿？
We hit up a couple of local bars and met up with some friends.
我们去了几家当地的酒吧，和一些朋友碰了面。
Everything was cool until Mike came along and it turned out that it was his birthday
本来一切都挺好的，直到Mike来了，结果发现昨天是他的生日。
yesterday.
昨天。
Oh no.
哦不。
Mike's birthday is a drink fest for sure.
Mike的生日肯定是一场喝酒狂欢。
Tell me about it.
可不是嘛。
We drank everything in the bar.
我们把酒吧里的酒都喝光了。
Is that why you missed work today?
这就是你今天没上班的原因吗？
Yeah, I woke up this morning feeling really nauseous.
是啊，我今天早上醒来觉得特别恶心。
I threw up like five times.
我吐了大概五次。
Ew.
恶心。
I was so dehydrated that I drank a gallon of water and my head has been pounding all
我脱水太严重了，喝了一加仑水，头一直疼得厉害。
day.
一整天。
I swear, I am never going to drink again.
我发誓，我再也不喝酒了。
Too bad, man.
真糟糕，老兄。
Tonight is Tracy's going away party and she asked if you were going to go.
今晚是特雷西的告别派对，她问你会不会去。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
I'm there.
我去。
So it sounds like these guys sure like to go out and have a few drinks, don't they?
看来这些人确实喜欢出去喝几杯，对吧？
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
And I think this is a very common thing among young people, usually in the United States.
我觉得这在年轻人中很常见，尤其是在美国。
After a day at the office or something, they'll go or even in Europe, they'll go to the pub,
下班后或者什么的，他们会去酒吧，甚至在欧洲，他们也会去酒吧，
right?
对吧？
Yeah.
对。
But the thing is that in America and Canada, we're very careful about alcohol and young
但问题是，在美国和加拿大，我们对酒精和年轻人非常谨慎，
people, right?
对吧？
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
The legal drinking age in the most part of the United States is 21 years of age.
美国大部分地区的法定饮酒年龄是21岁。
And really, many parents or families will never let their children drink alcohol until
而且，很多家长或家庭在孩子21岁之前绝不会让他们喝酒。
they're 21.
对。
Right.
And also the laws that control alcohol, like for example, on television, if you notice
还有控制酒精的法律，比如在电视上，如果你注意的话，
a TV commercial with a beer or a wine, you will never see the person actually drinking
一个啤酒或葡萄酒的电视广告，你永远不会看到有人真的在喝。
it.
这是违法的。
It's illegal.
对，没错。
Yeah, that's true.
对，确实如此。
While in other countries, it's okay.
而在其他国家，这没问题。
You'll see people drinking it and having fun.
你会看到人们喝酒并享受乐趣。
In these commercials, they can only maybe put them close to their lips but not drink
在这些广告里，他们只能把酒瓶靠近嘴唇，但不能喝。
it.
有意思。
Interesting.
I mean, another weird thing is that sometimes you might want to sit in your back garden
我是说，另一件奇怪的事是，有时候你可能想坐在后花园或门廊上，下班后喝杯啤酒，对吧？
or out on your porch and have a beer after work, right?
但在某些地方，这完全是违法的。
But in places, it's totally illegal to do that.
你不能在外面喝酒。
You can't be outside with alcohol.
对。
Right.
You can't be seen drinking or you can't be on the sidewalk or on a bus drinking.
你不能被人看到喝酒，也不能在人行道上或公交车上喝。
While in other places, you can, right?
而在其他地方，你可以，对吧？
You can just have a beer on the subway.
你甚至可以在地铁上喝啤酒。
So it's a little bit different policies on alcohol control.
所以酒精控制政策有点不同。
What do you guys think about it?
你们觉得呢？
Do you think it's correct or do you think maybe it's a little bit too exaggerated?
你们认为这是正确的，还是可能有点过于夸张了？
Come to our website, EnglishPod.com and tell us about it.
来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 告诉我们吧。
Alright.
好的。
We'll see you guys there and until next time.
我们会在那里见你们，下次再见。
Thanks for downloading and goodbye.
感谢下载，再见。